<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Galaxy, Tripal and Computational Analysis on Learn Galaxy and Tripal Galaxy</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Galaxy, Tripal and Computational Analysis on Learn Galaxy and Tripal Galaxy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Build Dataset Collection</title>
      <link>/use-galaxy/use-tools/build-dataset-collection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/use-galaxy/use-tools/build-dataset-collection/</guid>
      <description>Please refer to this page to see what dataset collection is and how to build dataset collections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build Workflow from Scratch</title>
      <link>/use-galaxy/build-workflows/build-workflow-from-scratch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/use-galaxy/build-workflows/build-workflow-from-scratch/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Launch Galaxy Instance</title>
      <link>/galaxy-setup/launch-galaxy-instance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/galaxy-setup/launch-galaxy-instance/</guid>
      <description>Docker Galaxy The Docker Galaxy image created by Björn Grüning is probably the mostly widely used Docker image for Galaxy. It has over 10k+ pulls from Docker hub. We are going to use this image to launch a Galaxy instance. Before we launch a Docker container, we need to get Docker installed. Instructions on Docker installation can be found on the offical Docker website.
Launch a Galaxy instance: docker run -i -t --rm \ -p 80:80 -p 8021:21 -p 8022:22 \ -e &amp;quot;ENABLE_TTS_INSTALL=True&amp;quot; \ -e &amp;quot;GALAXY_CONFIG_ADMIN_USERS=example@gmail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upload Local Data</title>
      <link>/use-galaxy/import-data/upload-local-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/use-galaxy/import-data/upload-local-data/</guid>
      <description>Upload local file To upload a local file, click Get Data-&amp;gt;Upload File on the left panel, then you will see the file uploading interface. Click Choose local file to upload your file.
Most of times, galaxy tools can automatically detect uploaded file types. But you can manually set type for a single file or all files when uploading files.
 Change data type You can also change the data type after the file has been uploaded to Galaxy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extract Workflow from History</title>
      <link>/use-galaxy/build-workflows/extract-workflow-from-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/use-galaxy/build-workflows/extract-workflow-from-history/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Import with FTP</title>
      <link>/use-galaxy/import-data/import-with-ftp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/use-galaxy/import-data/import-with-ftp/</guid>
      <description>Account info for target Galaxy Galaxy has limit on the size of uploaded files. Any thing larger than 2G requires transferring with FTP. To transfer files to a Galaxy instance with FTP, the target Galaxy has to have FTP data transfer enabled. And you will need your account email and password from the target Galaxy to transfer data.
Clicking User on the tool menu will display your account email.
 Connect to target Galaxy Make sure your source server have SFTP or FTP client installed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install Galaxy Tools</title>
      <link>/galaxy-setup/install-galaxy-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/galaxy-setup/install-galaxy-tools/</guid>
      <description>Register an admin account You need admin permission to install tools in Galaxy. Let’s create an admin account first. In the previous section, we have set example@gmail.com as an admin user email. We can use this email to register an admin account.
If you successfully registered an admin account, you should be able to see admin on the tool menu on the top.
 Install tools Click the admin button and then click Search Tool Shed on the left menu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Run Tools</title>
      <link>/use-galaxy/use-tools/run-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/use-galaxy/use-tools/run-tools/</guid>
      <description>Quality evaluation with Fastqc before trimming We select the FastQC tool on the tool panel on the left and select the dataset collection from the history we created. The remaining input fields use default values. Click Execute to run the job.
 Trimming reads with Trimmomatic Select Trimmomatic tool on the tool panel and the dataset collection we created as the input for the input FASTQ file, click Execute to run the job.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build up your own Galaxy image</title>
      <link>/galaxy-setup/build-up-your-own-galaxy-image/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/galaxy-setup/build-up-your-own-galaxy-image/</guid>
      <description>pre code, pre, code { white-space: pre !important; overflow-x: scroll !important; word-break: keep-all !important; word-wrap: initial !important; }  Build up your own Galaxy container The Galaxy Docker container we are using only has basic tools. Performing a complicated computational analysis can involve many many tools. We can install many tools into a Galaxy instance and save the installation work into a container. Next time when we need a Galaxy instance for data analysis, we can launch one with our own Galaxy container.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>View Results</title>
      <link>/use-galaxy/use-tools/view-results/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/use-galaxy/use-tools/view-results/</guid>
      <description>View results Click the eye icon on the right of any output on the history panel to view the file.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Download Results</title>
      <link>/use-galaxy/use-tools/download-results/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/use-galaxy/use-tools/download-results/</guid>
      <description>Download single dataset We can select a single dataset on the history panel and click the Download icon to download the dataset from Galaxy to your local computer.
 Download multiple datasets Galaxy allows you to export the entire history. It also allows you to copy datasets from one history to a new history. We can use this as a strategy to download multiple datasets at once.
Click the History options icon and then select copy datasets.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>